

ANDRE GABRIEL V. ALVAREZ

A full-stack developer with three years of extensive working experience in developing, improving, and maintaining systems such as company landing page, employee management system and production incident management system. Seeking to gain more knowledge and growth towards web development and software engineering.



+63 956 832 2121



(🖾) andregvalvarez@gmail.com



http://andrealvarez.rf.qd

Education

Mapúa Malayan Colleges Laguna

Jun. 2015 - Dec. 2019 Bachelor of Science Major in Computer Science Specializing in Software Engineer

Canossa School Sta. Rosa Laguna

Jun. 2005 - Mar. 2015 Studied from Elementary to High School

Skills

Programming Languages:

C#, C++, PHP, VBA, Java, JavaScript

Development Tools:

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Laravel, ASP.Net, Photoshop

Databases:

MySQL, MSSQL

Affiliation

Junior Philippine Computer Society (JPCS)

Jun. 2015 - Dec 2019 Vice President AY 2018-2019

Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)

Jul. 2018 - Dec 2019 Member

Work Experience

IT Staff (System Maintenance)

March 2021 - Present

Brother Industries Philippines, Inc.

- Developed systems using tools such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ASP.Net MVC framework, Visual Basic for Web Applications, MSSQL, and Microsoft Excel VBA to provide solutions and improve processes of work inside the company.
- Reduced production delays by building a system that serves as repository of guides and manages incidents to resolve reoccurrences.
- Maintained and administered existing source codes, and databases.
- Established manuals, procedures, and regulations to standardize work processes.
- Responded to and resolved software and hardware-related problems.
- Collaborated with partner companies to resolve technical problems.

HR Assistant (MIS Section)

January 2020 - February 2021

International Elevator and Equipment, Inc.

- Administered and upgraded in-house Human Resources Information System.
- Simplified processes and optimized system and database performance.
- Prepared and analyzed reports such as graphs and charts.
- Created graphics and illustrations for company's special occasions and events.
- Answered and resolved technical difficulties inside the office.

Backend Developer

March 2019 - May 2019

Gleent, Inc. (OJT)

- Developed solutions based on clients' requests and needs using web development tools such as PHP, Laravel framework and MySQL.
- Engaged in developing functionalities such as data output, dynamic report generation and, PDF and e-mail manipulation.

Training

- Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design
- Agile Development and Building Effective IT Teams
- Introduction to UX and AI
- Introduction to Python and Data Science
- Introduction to Big Data and Analytics
- Web Services: Usage and Framework in Mobile Application
- Relevance of ISO20000 to Future IT Professionals in the ITSM Industry